<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>csharp - Tag - &gt;_lluis franco</title>
        <link>http://lluisfranco.com/tags/csharp/</link>
        <description>csharp - Tag - &gt;_lluis franco</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>hello@lluisfranco.com (lluís)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hello@lluisfranco.com (lluís)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 11:51:50 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://lluisfranco.com/tags/csharp/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Extract extra large icon from a file, folder or drive</title>
    <link>http://lluisfranco.com/extract-icons-win32/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 11:51:50 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://lluisfranco.com/extract-icons-win32/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/extra-large-icons.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Extracting system icons from Win32 Overwiew Hi, everyone! :)
In a recent project I was required to show a list of files with their associated icons. It doesn&rsquo;t sounds quite difficult, and in fact it is not. Except if you have to deal with files in network paths or you want to get different icons sizes, apart the typical 32×32. And well, that was the case <i class="fas fa-grin-beam-sweat"></i>
If you only need local files and sizes of 32x32 píxels you can achieve this using the static method ExtractAssociatedIcon in the class System.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Check if current user is domain administrator</title>
    <link>http://lluisfranco.com/check-current-user-is-domain-admin/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 11:51:50 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://lluisfranco.com/check-current-user-is-domain-admin/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/sysadmin.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The scenario In business applications it’s very common checking if the current user is member of the ‘domain administrators’ role of your company. For example, recently I had to check if the current user has administrative privileges in order to show some advanced configuration options.
IsInRole To acomplish this we could use the IsInRole method from the WindowsPrincipal class. This method checks if an user is member of a Windows role and returns a bool value.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Retrieve all controls using generics (II)</title>
    <link>http://lluisfranco.com/retrieve-all-controls-using-generics-ii/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 17:20:51 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://lluisfranco.com/retrieve-all-controls-using-generics-ii/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/tshirt2.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Gettings all controls from a container v2 A better approach In my previous post I created a recursive function to retrieve all controls inside a form and its containers. Today, my colleague and friend Eduard Tomàs sent me another solution to the same topic based on LINQ. It’s simply and really, really pretty ❤️
The power of LINQ Before starting, we need to solve this: LINQ works over IEnumerable, but Control.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Retrieve all controls using generics (I)</title>
    <link>http://lluisfranco.com/retrieve-all-controls-using-generics-i/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 17:20:51 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://lluisfranco.com/retrieve-all-controls-using-generics-i/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/tshirt.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Gettings all controls from a container That&rsquo;s the question How many times have you ever heard something similar? :)
 How to clear the content of all the textboxes in a form?
 The question may vary a littles bit but it&rsquo;s always related to obtain all controls of a determined type (Button TextBox, etc) in a form or maybe in another type of container like a Panel or user control.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
